Who's afraid?
Red Riding Hood is a thriller, drama, fantasy film
directed by Catherine Hardwicke.
Valerie is in love with a brooding outsider, Peter, but her
parents have arranged for her to marry another man.
Unwilling to lose each other, Valerie and Peter plan to run away together when Valerie's older
sister is killed by a werewolf that prowls the dark forest surrounding their village.
Panic grips the town as Valerie discovers that she has a unique connection to the
beast--one that inexorably draws them together, making her both suspect ...
Valerie, played by Amanda Seyfried.
Father Soloman, played by Gary Oldman.
Cesaire, played by Billy Burke.
Peter, played by Shiloh Fernandez.
Henry Lazar, played by Max Irons.
Valerie's Grandmother, played by Julie Christie.
Red Riding Hood is a 2011 American romantic fantasy horror film directed by Catherine Hardwicke,
and produced by Leonardo DiCaprio, from a screenplay by David Leslie Johnson.
The film is very loosely based on the folk tale "Little Red Riding Hood" collected by both Charles Perrault under the name Le Petit
Chaperon Rouge (Little Red Riding Hood) and several decades later by the Brothers Grimm as Rotkäppchen (Little Red Cap).
It stars Amanda Seyfried as the title role, with Gary Oldman, Billy Burke, Shiloh Fernandez,
Max Irons, Virginia Madsen, Lukas Haas and Julie Christie in supporting roles.
Red Riding Hood had its world premiere at Hollywood on March 7, 2011, and
was theatrically released on March 11, 2011, by Warner Bros.
The film received negative reviews, and was a box-office success,
grossing $98 million worldwide against its $42 million budget.
The film explores themes of winter, fairy tale,
little red riding hood, hood, werewolf.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.